[The Journey of Legend]
[Episode 22]
The Fire King still failed in the end.
Li Chenzhou, Liu Suifeng,
you two are not half bad.
But unfortunately,
it is all too late.
The martial world is already in chaos.
I've made proper arrangements
for the Northern Wasteland.
Everything is under my control.
However resourceful you are,
you'll never figure out why I can
always get one step ahead of you.
[Liang Residence]
Big Brother?
Big Brother, you're finally back.
Just now, you...
You've regained all your martial strength!
Big Brother!
Are you okay?
If you had hit me any harder,
I wouldn't be okay at all.
Yuhan,
Big Brother's meridians
have truly fully recovered.
Even his internal energy
has increased significantly.
This is great.
Guys,
thank you so much
for taking care of me in recent days.
I have finally returned from the dead.
Enough chitchat.
Where is
Grand Master Dayin?
Mr. Liang,
Grand Master Dayin,
Thank you two for your help.
Now, I'm all fine.
Mr. Xiao,
are you still feeling off
about your meridians?
No, I don't think there's a problem.
Master, maybe you can check my pulse.
Congratulations, Mr. Xiao.
Your meridians
are even smoother and stronger
now than before.
There is a powerful stream
of internal energy within you.
You must've had many adventures
after I gave you acupuncture therapy.
Grand Master Dayin,
actually, I got that energy
from the Infinite Pill.
Surprisingly, after Shao Liulei forced me
to take that pill,
I attained a surge of energy
that amounted to 60 years of practice.
Big Brother,
you ate the Infinite Pill?
That explains why I was shocked
by your internal energy just now.
What an incredible experience
you had, Big Brother.
Where is Shao Liulei then?
He is dead now.
The Infinite Pill fell in
the hands of 3 people:
Crazy Yan, Shao Liulei, and me.
Not only has the Power Gang
been trying to claim it,
but also Zhu the Great King
has been looking for this pill.
Zhu the Great King is involved too?
It seems things are about to get chaotic.
Wudang Sect and Shaolin Sect will see
the Power Gang as their arch enemy.
In order to dominate the martial world,
the Power Gang
will be even more unscrupulous.
The Power Gang
has never stopped doing evil.
I believe that one day,
they will be eliminated
by the righteous members
of the martial world.
Qiushui,
though you have
stronger internal energy now,
you're not skilled in martial arts yet.
You need to stay humble
and continue your sword practice.
Just wait for the right time
to take revenge.
Don't worry, Mr. Liang.
That's what I'm thinking too.
Mr. Xiao,
you saved my life.
Destiny has brought us together.
I'd like to teach you
the Energy Taming Technique,
which I'm best at.
If you regulate your breathing and power
with this technique,
you'll become better at
controlling your internal energy.
Thank you, Grand Master Dayin.
Terrific.
Now that Qiushui is back,
let's have a celebration tonight.
Mr. Liang,
I appreciate your kindness.
But there's no need for a celebration.
I ended Kang Chuyu's life
with my very own hands.
Guys,
we've finally avenged Tang Rou.
Great.
Tang Rou can finally
rest in peace, Big Brother.
Finally, we took revenge for Tang Rou.
I only regret
that I didn't get to help with it.
Oh, right.
I found this on Kang Chuyu.
I suspect he was somehow
connected to the Power Gang.
See what you can find out.
Okay. We'll take care of it.
Stay cautious.
Mr. Xiao,
something has been puzzling me.
I had been to the Sword Manor.
It was impenetrable.
How did it end up being broken?
What exactly happened?
Has the truth been revealed yet?
That day, we were besieged
by the Power Gang.
With the solid Sword Manor's help,
we could have held out.
But the loyal Mr. Qiu
suddenly turned against us.
He poisoned the water sources in secret,
so our water supply was cut off.
Staying in the Sword Manor
was equal to waiting for death.
Given that, my parents
chose to give
their chance of survival to us.
This is what they said,
"Son,
get out of this place at all costs.
Make sure you keep yourself safe."
But by the time we returned,
the Sword Manor had already fallen.
I couldn't find my parents' bodies.
Xueyu set up cenotaphs for them.
I also find Mr. Qiu's betrayal odd.
I once paid a visit to Xilou years ago.
Mr. Qiu was the one who received me.
He had no desire and was all alone.
Neither did he have any family
to be threatened with.
Why would he suddenly
switch to the Power Gang's side?
It's said that the Power Gang
owns an evil thing called the Misery Pill
that plunges people into abject suffering.
They use that to coerce the righteous
into betrayal and submission.
That's what
makes the Power Gang invincible,
and as influential as they are today.
The Misery Pill...
Betrayal and submission...
Mr. Liang,
Grand Master Dayin,
after hearing what you two said,
it suddenly occurred to me
that Mr. Qiu might have been harmed
that way.
How about
we examine his body now?
Okay.
Beware of the toxins from the corpse.
Hold your breath now.
So the culprit was this thing.
It's a Death Beetle
produced by the Ghost King.
I bet the Misery Pill
is hidden inside this Death Beetle.
You're right.
This Death Beetle is a living creature.
When it crawls into a person's body,
carrying the Misery Pill,
the Power Gang
can badly torture this person
by controlling the Death Beetle.
So, whether this person
attempts to survive
or to relieve himself
of agony through death,
he's bound to be used by the Power Gang.
I think all the righteous sects
should assemble and unite immediately.
Otherwise,
they'll be conquered one by one.
The Power Gang use such beetles
to manipulate people.
How horrifying.
I can't imagine
how many other people
will fall victims the same way.
Don't worry, Qiushui.
I'm with the Xiao family,
no matter what happens.
Grand Master Dayin and I will help you
with all our might.
Big Brother, don't worry.
Liu Suifeng is backed by the Power Gang.
And you're backed by us,
the Shenzhou Sworn Brotherhood.
Good.
[Virtues Always Prevail]
[Energy Taming Technique]
♪ Wishing to borrow
the body of a firefly ♪
♪ To see the world,
to see all living beings ♪
♪ Then borrow the wind and snow,
the bone-deep cold ♪
♪ To bring a spring
free of chill next year ♪
♪ If the long night is hard to pierce ♪
♪ I banish all sorrows from my heart ♪
♪ Only to end up like a falling leaf ♪
♪ If the long night is hard to pierce ♪
♪ Then tear open the darkness ♪
♪ Hold a tiny flame, light a lone lamp ♪
♪ Let my body be the chess piece,
entering this labyrinth ♪
♪ Journey into the cage once more ♪
♪ Hoping that
amid the dark wind and rain ♪
♪ I can glimpse a sliver of sky ♪
♪ Though the path be all frost and storm ♪
♪ Though life may have no companion ♪
♪ I have no regrets,
and the heart moves onward ♪
♪ Why fear the ups and downs of life? ♪
♪ Treat life and death as no big deal ♪
♪ There might not be light ahead ♪
♪ But my dream is a beacon ♪
♪ I respect the short-lived insects ♪
♪ I respect the ambitious insects ♪
♪ Wait for the fog to disperse
and the sun to set ♪
♪ Wishing to borrow
the body of a firefly ♪
Third Young Master,
the letters written to Miss Tang
have all been returned.
♪ In exchange for warmth
in my palms and heart ♪
[To Tang Rou]
[Xiao Residence]
[Huanhua Sect]
Yiren.
Xueyu.
You've been working so hard lately.
I made some nerve-soothing soup
specially for you.
Thank you.
It does cost a lot
to rebuild Huanhua Sect.
Renovating buildings,
reforging iron tools, regrouping forces...
So many matters to attend to.
You can't rush any of those.
Over half of our savings
have been exhausted.
Now, Kaiyan and I are
working our tails off to raise funds.
But it's still hard
to bridge the financial gap.
The sects
that used to be friendly with us in Jindu
have all chosen to leave us in the lurch.
I think we should pursue a different path
to revitalize the Xiao family.
As long as we make concerted efforts,
I believe we will find a solution.
Alright.
Enough talk about these troubling matters.
It's very late now.
Why haven't you gone to bed?
I tried to sleep,
but then awakened from a dream.
Was something bothering you?
Yiren,
do you know what I just dreamed about?
I can't believe
I dreamed about my childhood.
Back then,
I was with my birth parents.
In a spacious courtyard,
I would fly kites with my brother.
What a beautiful scene.
Indeed.
You parted with your birth parents
at a young age.
But since you came to the Xiao family,
we've all treated you as one of our own.
Yes.
I've felt warm and welcome
all the time since I came.
Father, Mother, you, Kaiyan,
and Qiushui...
We've always spoken our thoughts
out loud to one another.
What a happy family.
However, since that misfortune
befell the Xiao family,
everyone has become too anxious.
You are,
and so is Qiushui.
But I believe,
no matter what happens,
the fact that we are family
will never change.
Our hearts should stick together.
You're right.
As the eldest brother,
I didn't mean to lash out at Qiushui.
By the time I reopened the family's door
that day,
I had suffered enough
contempt and humiliation.
But he had the gall
to accuse me of cashing in past favors
to milk benefits.
That day, he just spoke out of turn
in the heat of the moment.
Yiren,
stop being mad at him.
It's common
for family members to bicker, right?
This is not an irreconcilable conflict.
After some time,
I'll invite Kaiyan and Qiushui
for a meal with us, so...
Enough.
Our priority is to reopen Huanhua Sect.
I'm currently reaching out
to the major sects
and seeking assistance from afar.
I don't have time for Qiushui.
Besides,
he's not a child anymore.
It's time he thought about his future.
The falconry whistle...
The Death Beetle...
The Power Gang...
Big Brother!
Big Brother.
Something on your mind?
Can't you tell?
It's written all over Big Brother's face:
"Tang Fang, why don't you talk to me?"
"Tang Fang, are you still mad at me?"
"Tang Fang,
when will I get to see you again?"
Can you stop saying nonsense?
I just want to clear up
misunderstandings.
Oh, right.
How's the investigation
on the falconry whistle going?
We're still looking into it.
There will be findings in a few days.
You brought only one jar of wine?
This is premium wine.
A jar of wine for the 3 of us.
Big Brother, you go first.
Sounds good.
It's really nice. Your turn.
I go second!
Shouldn't it be my turn?
[Huanhua Sect]
I told them to come
and pay rent at 9:45 a.m.
Now, it's already past noon.
Yet none of them have shown up.
Young Master, Tang Sect is holding
an ancestral worship ceremony today.
All of those we invited
have gone to Tang Sect for it.
What?
Tang Sect usually holds such a ceremony
in the middle of the month.
Why did they choose
the beginning of the month this time?
I can't believe they picked today.
Tang Sect seized our land
and collided with our schedule.
They keep provoking us.
This is outrageous!
Come on, cheers. Fill your glasses.
Come sit down. Drink up.
Hello, Mr. Xiao.
We showed up uninvited,
not knowing Tang Sect is having a ceremony
today.
Sorry for the intrusion.
Don't say that.
Many from the martial sects
have come to watch the ceremony.
I shouldn't have negligently
forgotten to send you two an invitation.
My apologies.
I raise my glass to you, Sect Leader Xiao.
This is unnecessary.
On this joyous occasion,
I'd like to ask you a question.
Usually, Tang Sect holds
such an ancestral worship ceremony
on the fifteenth day of the month.
What made you suddenly host one today?
I just did what I was instructed to.
How am I supposed to know
why the elders made this decision?
Tang Sect has always kept a low profile
and seldom held gatherings.
But now, you've invited so many guests
to this grand ancestral worship ceremony.
Is it your master's idea?
Or did he deliberately schedule for this
to knowingly mess with
our fund raising event today?
Mr. Xiao, are you blaming me?
I didn't know
you had plans to raise funds today.
Suppose I did pick today for the ceremony,
you wouldn't have the guts
to disrupt it, would you?
You...
Fine.
The Xiao family will not forget
Tang Sect's hostility today.
By the way,
since the Xiao family
can barely sustain itself now,
all the disciples studying at your place
will be taken over by Tang Sect
from now on.
Boys!
Uncle Xiao is leaving.
Aren't you going to bid him farewell?
Goodbye, Uncle Xiao.
How dare you raid
our martial training hall?
Ungrateful punks!
We're not cutting ties
with the Xiao family!
The Xiao family has fallen from grace.
You can't even
make a few young trainees stay.
All I can say is that times have changed.
We've won over everyone.
Xiao Yiren,
trying to bluff
and intimidate others again
will only turn you into a laughing stock.
You...
You can't even
make a few young trainees stay.
What a disgrace!
You're inviting humiliation!
You've all used the land
of the Xiao family,
and benefited
from the Xiao family's generosity.
How could you turn on who has helped you?
Now, these lands no longer
belong to the Xiao family.
What's the point
of harping on the tiny favors
you did us before?
Butler Nangong,
I can't believe you're here too!
Mr. Nangong is absolutely right.
Now, the land
on which we train our members
is leased from the Nangong family,
and has nothing to do
with the Xiao family anymore.
So now you have
all the small plots of land I sold?
That's right.
Now, the Nangong family and Tang Sect
are two strong forces in alliance.
From now all, all the affairs
in the Jindu martial community
will be handled by us.
It's time for the Xiao family,
which leads Huanhua Sect, to stop
clinging to its past glory!
-Yeah!
-Be realistic!
Go away!
Tang Sect and our family used to be
two equally strong powers in Jindu.
They already antagonized us at that time!
Now, our family has
just come crushing down,
they're already colluding with
the Nangong family
to take our people and land away!
Aren't they obviously trying to
to devour our family's resources
all at once?
Tang Sect's enmity is no surprise to me.
I just didn't expect the Nangong family
would discard our old friendship.
Tang Song sure is detestable,
but he did say something right just now.
Times have changed.
Back then, when the Nangong family
tried to gain a foothold in Jindu,
they had to rely on us, the Xiao family.
But today, we the Xiao family are
in need of the Nangong family's help.
However, the Nangong family
has now allied with
the powerful Tang Sect.
They'd just despise us even more,
wouldn't they?
They both specialize in the same field.
There is competition between them.
Perhaps
they're not as united as they appear.
Besides, we go way back
with the Nangong family.
If I drop my pride, cooperate with them,
and help them achieve their ambitions,
maybe they'll consider being our aide.
It's time to take action. You go home now.
Wait to hear from me.
[Nangong Residence]
How dare you disobey me!
No more dodging!
Kneel! On your knees!
Trying to dodge?
On your knees!
I'll beat you up!
Kneel!
Dodging?
Again?
This will teach you!
And you!
[Nangong Wushang]
Sect Leader Xiao.
Mr. Nangong.
Pardon me for being blunt.
I came here
with the hope of getting help
from the Nangong family,
for the sake of the friendship
between our two families,
so I can revive Huanhua Sect.
When the Xiao family returns to glory,
I promise that in Jindu,
he who knows the Xiao family
will also know the Nangong family.
How kind of you to say that.
In the Xiao family, you're the only
extraordinary martial fighter.
By contrast, Tang Sect is flourishing
and showing great momentum.
Why should the Nangong family
ally with the Xiao family?
It's true that Tang Sect is powerful now,
but people's minds
change every now and then.
Maybe their strength
will turn into a hinderance one day.
Our two families
have been friends for years.
Aren't we more reliable than outsiders?
By that logic,
the Nangong family is not exactly closely
bound with the Xiao family.
Mr. Xiao, how can you guarantee
the Xiao family is reliable?
Wushang's concerns
are indeed reasonable.
-Mr. Nangong.
-Brother.
This is not an unsolvable problem.
If the Xiao family
is genuinely sincere about this,
I don't mind deepening the bond
between our two families.
Xiaoyi
is even closer to the Xiao family
than to us.
I suggest Xueyu marry into our family.
Xueyu?
No.
Marriage is a lifelong commitment,
which should be based on mutual affection.
How can it be used as a bargaining chip?
Then I don't think
the Xiao family is being sincere.
How can you expect us to help you?
But this shouldn't be
my sister's responsibility, right?
Fine.
You'd hate to maintain the ties
through marriage, right?
Then send the Xiao family's sword manual
to the Nangong family.
I'll keep it for you.
Then, I'll lend you a helping hand.
You mean Huanhua Sword Manual?
No way!
It's the treasure of the Xiao family,
and the lifeblood of Huanhua Sect.
How can I give it away?
You refused every request.
Do you want the Nangong family
to beg you instead?
I came here to ask for help
in good faith.
Never did I expect the Nangong family
to be so aggressive.
This conversation ends here then.
Show yourself out now.
Fine.
Goodbye!
Once you walk out that door,
the Power Gang and Tang Sect
won't the only two institutes
attempting to wipe the Xiao family
out of Jindu.
The Nangong family
always gets what it wants.
Thereafter, the Xiao family will no longer
have a place in the martial world.
You're choosing to
ruin the century-old foundation
of Huanhua Sect.
♪ Let this long river boil and burn ♪
♪ Reforge new mountains and seas ♪
♪ Let the gleam of swords
cut through all dust ♪
♪ Strive for the far shore
at journey's end ♪
♪ Only when the long night
finally comes to an end ♪
♪ Will this bow be not in vain ♪
♪ Let the pouring rain drench me ♪
♪ Let frost and snow embrace me too ♪
♪ My lifelong sword intent
remains unchanged ♪
♪ Through 1,000 years, a million ages ♪
♪ I will still cleave mountains
and carve paths ♪
♪ Waiting for the fog to clear,
waiting for the dawn and you to come ♪
♪ The violent storms ♪
♪ Thousands of turbid waves ♪
♪ Tread on through till the break of day ♪
♪ I'm ready to go with you ♪
♪ Let the pouring rain drench me ♪
♪ Let frost and snow embrace me too ♪
♪ My lifelong sword intent
remains unchanged ♪
♪ Through 1,000 years, a million ages ♪
♪ I will still cleave mountains
and carve paths ♪
♪ Waiting for the fog to clear,
waiting for the dawn and you to come ♪
Although I've absorbed
most of the Infinite Pill's power,
coordinating my internal energy
with sword techniques is still difficult.
Your father specifically asked me
to impart all the best techniques
of the Xiao family to you.
Mother,
did Father tell you to teach me
Tianque Technique?
It's fair to say
Tianque Technique is our family's
most challenging skill to learn.
Your father has only learned
the basics of it.
Though every descendant of the Xiao family
would memorize
the instructions of it in childhood,
they can't start practicing it
until the best timing comes.
Channel energy from Lingquan acupoint
and direct it to Taiyuan acupoint.
Clear the energy at Danzhong acupoint
and gather it at Geshu acupoint.
What are you doing?
Xueyu has never even
seen Nangong Wushang.
That guy is incompetent
and overly ambitious.
He can't make a good husband!
Yiren,
even if you are to
marry off Xueyu to a man,
you should find a better guy than that.
You think I'd like that to happen?
They came on me strong.
I meant to reject their proposal,
but they escalated their acts
and even asked for Huanhua Sword Manual.
How could the Nangong family
be so aggresive?
Yiren,
we watched Xueyu grow up.
Under no circumstances
should we put her in hot waters.
Given the current situation,
the Xiao family only has
the Nangong family to rely on.
They won't easily back off
until they get what they want.
They'll either be our in-laws or enemies.
What else can I do?
I'm only doing this
for Huanhua Sect and the Xiao family!
[Huanhua Sect]
[Pattering Rain]
I didn't know
you had plans to raise funds today.
Suppose I did pick today for the ceremony,
you wouldn't have the guts
to disrupt it, would you?
Now, the land
on which we train our members
is leased from the Nangong family,
and has nothing to do
with the Xiao family anymore!
The Nangong family
always gets what it wants.
Thereafter, the Xiao family will no longer
have a place in the martial world.
You're choosing to ruin
the century-old foundation
of Huanhua Sect.
Yiren,
I know you're upset
and having an urge for drinks.
But Huanhua Sect needs you.
Why are you still here?
Now, the Xiao family
is not good enough
for the Nangong family, is it?
You should quickly follow
your brother and father
to seek a bright future in Tang Sect.
I've heard about
what happened in Tang Sect.
It was the Nangong family's fault.
We've failed your family's trust.
I already wrote my family a letter,
declaring to cut ties with them.
What?
You...
There's a certain code of honor
in the martial world.
One can't take advantage of
those who are already down.
Indeed.
I did think of the code of honor
as the most important.
But now, everyone has chosen
benefits and power
over everything else.
I, Xiao Yiren,
swear to take back
what the Xiao family has lost,
and to make those snobs regret.
My Lady, bad news!
The Nangong family has sent people here.
Wushang.
Don't call me that.
Didn't you decide to sever ties with me?
From today on,
you are no longer
part of the Nangong family.
You're not allowed to step foot
in Nangong Residence.
Mr. Nangong,
Xiaoyi has nothing to do with this matter.
[Huanhua Sword Manual]
Huanhua Sword Manual?
You...
It's your fault for being too incompetent.
You even failed to
keep this important manual safe.
Those young traitors of the Xiao family
got hold of it effortlessly.
How despicable of them
to stab the Xiao family in the back.
If Huanhua Sword Manual
reaches every corner,
and the technique inside
is mastered by everyone,
then Huanhua Sect
will be completely dispensable
in the martial world, right?
I don't know
how you obtained Huanhua Sword Manual.
But if you want to spread it around,
then just do it.
Now, you've come to stir up trouble.
You must be up to something.
How clever and lovely of you, Xueyu.
Are you going to force Xueyu to marry you?
What do you mean by "force"?
I lost a little sister to the Xiao family,
so they must give one back to me
to compensate for our family's loss.
Mr. Nangong,
do you have to go to the extreme
on this matter?
Xiao Yiren,
I'll give you a chance.
Marry off Xueyu to me,
and this manual will be
her betrothal gift.
Then, you can have it back.
If you reject...
And then what?
You have 5 days to mull this over.
If I don't get an answer in 5 days,
the Nangong family will see to it
that the Xiao family
disappears from Jindu.
Wushang!
[Liang Residence]
[Teamwork]
Big Brother,
there's a finding about the item
you asked me to look into.
Have you found out
the origin of that falconry whistle?
We've got some leads.
Also, we've found
that the Power Gang
is investigating the same thing.
We raided some dens in particular.
After comparing those people's statements,
we realized
this falconry whistle probably came from
[Investigate this item thoroughly]
a mysterious organization
linking to the Northern Wasteland.
A token from the Northern Wastelanders?
Yes, it is.
Besides, this organization
has infiltrated the Power Gang.
Two days ago,
the Fire King of the Eight Kings
was executed by Liu Suifeng and his people
for betraying the Power Gang
and colluding with
the falconry whistle's owner.
The Power Gang then demanded
a thorough investigation about this.
This item was taken from Kang Chuyu.
Kang Chuyu was the Sword King's confidant.
Is Qu Hanshan
working for the Northern Wasteland?
But with Qu Hanshan's identity
having been exposed,
he has long disappeared
from Guangling.
As luck would have it,
Qu Hanshan is in Jindu now.
He's in Jindu?
To catch the mole,
the chief of the Power Gang, Li Chenzhou,
had Liu Suifeng play
a trick of self-injury.
Unexpectedly,
the Sword King fell for it too.
Qu Hanshan and Liu Suifeng
have never got along.
With Liu Suifeng going down,
Qu Hanshan thought he'd become
the deputy chief.
However, in the end,
he didn't get that satisfaction.
He must be furious right now.
Although we haven't
located the Power Gang's headquarters,
someone has revealed Qu Hanshan's address.
He's living in the nearby Tongfu Street.
Liu Suifeng and Qu Hanshan
have always been at odds.
It's time we took
advantage of the rivalry between them.
Big Brother,
suppose Qu Hanshan
did collude with the Northern Wasteland,
he must be feeling antsy now,
as the Power Gang
is trying hard to catch moles.
You're right.
People make bad decisions in desperation.
This time,
I'm going to trick him.
Take a look. High-quality products.
Any different patterns?
Just a sec. I'll show you some.
How about this one?
Master.
Has Kang Chuyu come back?
Where has he gone?
The Sword King's mansion
is heavily guarded.
I need to find a way to sneak in.
This guy looks like Li Cai. How come?
I'm sorry. I'm terribly sorry.